AMS Standard Cover Sheet

Last Name: <u>Gustafson</u>	Middle Name:
First Name: Paul	
Complete mailing address:	Home Phone
2709 Rustling Oaks Dr	
Bryan, TX 77802	e-mail address
	paul.gustafson@gmail.com
Current Institutional Affiliation:	Skype Name
Graduate Student, May 2013-Present	Work Phone
Texas A&M University	Cell Phone
Mathematics	
Highest Degree held or expected PhD	
Granting Institution <u>Texas A&M University</u>	Date (optional) <u>05/2018 expected</u>
Ph.D. Advisor: <u>Eric Rowell</u>	
Thesis Title (optional) On the Property F Conjection	cture
Primary Interest (MSC# only)	Secondary Interests (optional) <u>16, 20</u>
Give a very brief synopsis of your current research in	terests in the box below (e.g. finite group actions on four-manifolds).
gories, mapping class groups, quantum groups, u http://www.math.tamu.edu/~pgustafs/ Most recent position held, if any, post Ph.D.	нишені иерениені type meories
	Dates
Indicate the position for which you are applying a	
University of Southern California	na position posting code, if applicable
Eligible for positions which requires U.S. citizensh	ip or U.S. permanent residency: X Yes No
If unsuccessful for this position, would you like to	
$\overline{\mathbb{X}}$ Yes \square No If yes, please check the ap	- • -
<i>v</i>	$X = \mathbb{Z}$ 2+ Year Position $X = 1$ Year Position
List the names and affiliations of individuals who	
1. Eric Rowell, Texas A&M University, rowe	ell@math.tamu.edu
2. Peter Howard, Texas A&M University, ph	oward@math.tamu.edu (teaching)
3. Richard Ng, Louisiana State University, rr	ng@math.lsu.edu
4. Sarah Witherspoon, Texas A&M Universit	y, sjw@math.tamu.edu
5. Zhenghan Wang, University of California,	Santa Barbara, zhenghwa@math.ucsb.edu
6. Peter Kuchment, Texas A&M University,	kuchment@math.tamu.edu (teaching)
7. Thomas Kerler, The Ohio State University	$y,\ kerler.2@osu.edu$

Paul Gustafson

pgustafs@math.tamu.edu https://github.com/PaulGustafson (979)774-9184

Work Experience

Texas A&M University

2013 - Present

PhD Candidate, Department of Mathematics

Knowledge Based Systems, Inc.

2011 - 2012

Programmer Analyst Summer 2008, Summer 2010

Education

Texas A&M University

2013 – Present

Doctor of Philosophy in Mathematics May 2018 (Expected)

Advisor: Eric Rowell

Texas A&M University

2012-2013

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

2013

Princeton University

2007 - 2011

Research Interests

Topological quantum computation, 3-manifold and link invariants, topological quantum field theories, fusion categories, mapping class groups, quantum groups, univalent dependent type theories

Publications and Preprints

- P. Bruillard, P. Gustafson, J. Plavnik, E. C. Rowell, Categorical Dimension as a Quantum Statistic and Applications, arXiv:1710.10284, submitted.
- P. Gustafson, Finiteness for Mapping Class Group Representations from Twisted Dijkgraaf-Witten Theory, arXiv:1610.06069, submitted.
- R. Fernandes, B. Li, K. Vadakkeveedu, A. Verma, P. Gustafson, et al., Agent-based analysis of trustworthiness in wireless sensor networks, *Proc. SPIE* **8407**, Multisensor, Multisource Information Fusion: Architectures, Algorithms, and Applications 2012, 84070W (May 1, 2012); doi:10.1117/12.920781.
- P. Gustafson, N. Savir, E. Spears, A Characterization of Refinable Rational Functions, Am. J. Undergrad. Res. 5 (3): 11-20 (Nov. 11, 2006).

Conference Presentations

AMS Special Session on Quantum Symmetries, The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH, March 2018.

AMS Special Session on Tensor Categories: Bridging Algebra, Topology, and Physics, U. C. Riverside, CA, November 2017.

AMS Special Session on Invariants of Links and 3-Manifolds, U. North Texas, Denton, TX, September 2017.

AMS Special Session on Fusion Categories and Applications, Indiana University, Bloomington, IN, April 2017.

AMS Special Session on Fusion Categories and Topological Phases of Matter, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT, April 2016.

Teaching Experience (Texas A&M University)

Mentor

REU on Mathematics of Topological Quantum Computation

Summer 2017

Instructor of Record

Mathematical Concepts – Calculus (M131)

Spring 2017

Teaching Assistant

Engineering Mathematics II (M152) Engineering Mathematics I (M151) Fall 2015, Spring 2018 Spring 2016, Fall 2017

Grader

Algebraic Topology I (M643)

Fall 2016

Counselor

SMaRT High School Math Camp

Summer 2009, Summer 2010

Code Repository

stringnet

https://github.com/PaulGustafson/stringnet

A Haskell library for calculating with quantum mapping class group representations

Workshop Participation

School and Workshop on Univalent Mathematics, University of Birmingham, UK, December 2017.

AMS Mathematical Research Community on Homotopy Type Theory, Snowbird, UT, June 2017.

Agda Implementors' Meeting XXV, Gothenburg, Sweden, May 2017.

Graduate Workshop on Topological Quantum Field Theory, Simons Center for Geometry and Physics, Stony Brook, NY, August 2015.

Oregon Programming Languages Summer School, University of Oregon, July 2013.

Programming Languages

Haskell, Agda, Coq, Python, C, Java, MATLAB, NetLogo